the creative Sound Blaster xj6 amazing
device but is it worth it for the PS5
let's find out originally priced at
129.99 here in UK nowadays is constantly
on sale between 80 and 90 pounds there's
a 1.2 meter long micro USB to USB a
cable and a mini tosling to tosling
Cable in the Box
the device is completely made out of
plastic there's a digital volume dial at
the front which is accompanied by a
combo Jack so if your headset only has
one 3.5 object of mic will still work
there's also a separate mic check next
to it on the side of the device we have
three buttons one is for the Scout mode
the other is SBX and this one is a
switch for low and high gain
the rear we have a line and Optical in
and line and Optical out and the micro
USB port which is used for connection
and Power
the bottom of the device has this
massive rubber insert so on the desk it
stays securely
the setup and changes on the device only
done through the creative Sound Blaster
command software which is on the PC or
Mac there's a very handy guide
explaining what these different options
do we get a very nice 10 band EQ option
which one set will be saved onto the
device playback have different options
for the audio quality I found 24 bit 48
kilohertz to be the best for some reason
and a recording we have some very nice
and funny voice move options but
unfortunately they are only available on
the PC and don't work on the PlayStation
5.
so there are two ways of using the
device in the PS5 one with a USB only
method with very simple I'll just plug
the USB the system picks it up the other
is using a HDMI audio instructor let's
quickly take a look at the USB only
method the device is plugged in
and in our sound settings we can see the
input device is recognize the soundblast
xj6 and you can adjust the microphone
level and stuff the output again USB
headset if you're using the USB only
method we need to make sure the
headphones output the headphones set to
all audio
with the USB you have the ability to
enable 3D audio as well which is a big
Plus in my opinion
so now I have a setup with the HDMI
audio structure and feeding the device
with the optical input as well I'm just
quickly going to show you what we need
to do in terms of the settings on the
PS5
so only thing we need to change
is we need to go to the audio output and
the output to headphones we need to
change it to voice chat audio only this
will enable our HDMI device type we need
to change that from TV to AV amplifier
and change the channels from 2 to 5.1
this is what creative suggests and I got
the best results whilst you're doing
this as well
so just quickly going to show you guys
the operation on the device itself so
when the LED lights are white on by the
volume dial this means that we are in
the global volume control so the LEDs do
go brighter and dimmer depending what
you are doing if you press and hold the
dial it will turn red now when you turn
red there is a LED light on this side if
it's blinking that means your side tone
is disabled when it's ready if you pass
it one more time when the light is solid
that means the side tones being enabled
now if I change the if I basically move
the dial we can adjust how much of the
side tone you are hearing in your
headset
and if I want to disable it same thing I
need to make sure that I'm in the red
LED mode press it one more time LED this
tiny microphone LED blinking means that
the most iPhone has been disabled now if
I have the optical in and I press and
hold one more time
the top LED and the other LED they will
change green me so this is the voice mix
feature this you only get this if you
have the optical coming in if it's just
a USB if you were in the red mode you'll
go back into the into the white LED mode
so here what we do is if we rotate
counterclockwise now we're getting more
of the chat so blue LED means we're
getting more of the chat if we go all
the way when it blinks that means it's
just chat no game coming back is so when
it comes back to green that means we
have the perfect mix
and so this yellow orange is basically
now we're getting the game audio which
is counterclockwise if you do it so this
is like cutting out the chat and this is
just the game audio and blinking is that
we are the max so the same thing this is
like you bring it back to green that
means we have the perfect mixture of
both holding the volume dial again we
come back to the red LED and the white
LED here that means we are back into the
normal Global volume control
on this sides the buttons that we have
we can turn the Scout mode on off I
didn't like that the processing but this
is very useful the SBX button this when
the light is lit that means all the
processing I showed you that we set in
the command software that's been applied
right now if I press and turn it off
that means none of the the EQ and the
bass and whatever surround setting
nothing's been applied so you kind of
have some control over it press it again
now it's being applied so that's just a
quick overview of the function on the
device itself so let's talk about the
sound quality guys
I have to say using it in the USB only
mode playing Call of Duty was actually a
good experience I was using my e-port86
Pros which I had trouble getting a
decent volume out of from the GSX 300 in
the controller and this even in low gain
I just couldn't use those at full volume
so it was a very very decent experience
Battlefield was not that good so when I
got the optical in that's when this
thing really basically came to life and
uh using the optical the HTML audio
extraction and the optical setup
Battlefield has been absolutely amazing
I've heard people you know their pain
Point accuracy of the audio where it is
coming from the audio separation it's
mind-blowing people flanking you you
just hear them I I do this thing where I
change the scope so I can basically have
a bit of an upper hand in a close
quarter battle and then change it when
you know somebody's far away
absolutely amazing so for me
I think this device is only worth with
uh with the optical setup so now this is
the the value proposition basically
should you get this if you only have a
PS5 and if you don't have a PC I don't
think so I think you definitely need a
PC there is a way of using it without a
PC so you just completely turn
everything off because originally when
it comes out of the box there are a lot
of different things apply to it and if
you are using it in the USB mode you
need to make sure you don't have any of
the SBX processing done only the EQ that
you're doing so you kind of definitely
need a PC I wish there was a mobile app
or better an app on the PlayStation 5
itself so if you don't have an access to
a PC this is definitely not the device I
would I think the Sound Blaster X4
because they have the mobile app support
and it's got the optical in I think that
would be more suitable but if you have
an access to a a computer or a Mac and
you want to upgrade your audio I think
this is a really amazing I used it with
the A6 Pro open back the Sun as a HD 598
anything I put into it just sounded
absolutely amazing but that's with the
HDMI audio instructor without it it's
yeah it just gives you louder volume
it's a it's still decent but something
like the GSX 300 can sort of work as
well but at 80 pounds I have to say I
love this device I've recently acquired
the steelseries game deck Gen 2 so
please you know keep an eye out on my
channel I'll be doing a comparison of
that with this because that only has USB
and it has some features and stuff so
I'll be making a detailed comparison I
hope there was some useful information
in this video if I left anything out if
you want to know anything else about
this device please do leave me a comment
and I want to thank you to everyone who
subscribed your support means a lot I
really really appreciate it and
hopefully I'll catch you in one of my
next videos thanks for watching this one
bye